TARUN SHARMA

601, Retro Avenues, Sec-2A, Koparkhairane, Navi-Mumbai, Maharashtra

M: 91-9650975757. E: tarunsharma2006@gmail.com L: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tarun-sharma-20975411

SUMMARY

Seasoned digital media professional with over eleven years of experience in all aspects of building digital products and monetization via ad-tech ecosystem. Have worked in different capacities with early stage startups to India's largest telecom network to build and monetize the next generation cross device advertising and engagement platform.

Skills: Product management, Product prototyping, GotoMarket strategy, Strategic alliances, Budgeting & Forecasting, Audience analytics, Performance marketing, Problem solving.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jio Platforms Limited - October 2017 to Present

Sr. Product Manager

- **JioAds Push** Product lead for push notification tool to improve customer engagement and increasing retention.
- Defined a roadmap for this product and ownership for ensuring sprint based on-time feature developments.
- Successfully did a soft launch on AOSP devices, catering to 2.5 Mn end users.
- Cross functional team management to ensure every stake holder is in sync with product requirement.
- Ensuring requirement docs, wire frames are communicated to relevant teams. Well versed with project tools like Trello, Jira, Azure.
- Partnered with In-house app owners for integrating Push SDK. On boarded 10 internal publishers within in 3 months.
- Built in-house B2B portal user interface (UI) for stakeholders to plan, execute & analyze the end user engagement.
- **JioAds** Integral part of the team that sets up Jio's digital ecosystem from ground up serving ads to 400 Mn users.
- Designed ads for Jiophones (kai OS) ecosystem leading to additional \$ 5 Mn in revenues.
- Built an audience management ensuring precise targeting that deliver the right ads to the right people basis their age, gender, interests, intent etc.
- Conceptualized and built a real time analytics portal user interface covering all product KPI's for better decision making.
- Defined processes for A/B testing executions to have better performance to achieve advertising goals of advertisers.
- Partnered with in-house and third-party app owners, sales and engineering teams to prioritize ad related sprint cycles basis product roadmap.
- Conducting product workshops for several internal teams to make them hands on about the product.

Kinobeo Software Pvt Ltd - November 2014 to October 2017

Sr. Manager – Mobile

- mydala.com Managed end to end life cycle for mweb and mobile app coupon & discount marketing platform.
- Revamped UI/UX and launched the both properties, resulting in 20% increase in engagement.
- Based on product improvements, brought uninstall rate by 25% within 1 year.
- Ownership of feature enhancements and bug fixes to ensure adoption is on incremental curve.
- Headed digital advertising for mydala app, mweb. P&L ownership for D2C products (mCoupon services).
- Built Annual operating plans, go-to-market strategies and drove them to successful execution.
- Managed user acquisitions on subscription and pay per view model via Facebook and ad networks.
- Saved 25% of annual marketing budget in acquiring the desired new acquisitions.
- Acquainted to tools like Appsflyer, Localytics, Google Analytics for data driven decision making.
- Handled a team of 4 members that drove business worth \$500,000 per month.

Hungama Digital Media Entertainment Pvt Ltd - July 2012 to September 2014

Assistant Manager – Mobile Marketing

• Spearheading subscription based user acquisition program for digital content of Indian movies.

- Managed various Mobile ad-network/agencies (Vserv, Google, Inmobi etc.) to have Product performance reviews.
- Handled revenue generation thru performance driven campaigns resulting in \$6 Mn annually.
- Delivered 80% growth in overall revenues during FY-13/14 as compared to FY-12/13.
- Closed commercial deals with ad-networks. Saved 20% of annual marketing budgets.
- Strategic account management Tata Docomo offering digital media services for GPRS subscribers.
- 40% annual revenue growth in revenues from client's B2B portals.
- Launched 3 new products in a year on client's wap portal.

Neomobile S.p.A - June 2010 to July 2012

Marketing Specialist

- Strategic account management Vodafone, Tata Indicom, Airtel offering text & rich media content
- Managed portfolio of products covering SMS, USSD and on-deck wap portals.
- Delivered the growth of 25% in Neomobile revenues through Airtel Live portal.
- Product management (D2C) Conceptualized and designed products for telco's wap portals.
- End to end ownership of new products and prepared go-to-market strategies.
- Content catalogue management/ life cycle management offered through B2B & D2C channels across all telecom operators in India.

Nazara Technologies Pvt Ltd - May 2009 to May 2010

Marketing Executive

- Strategic account management Real networks for Airtel live.
- Responsible for revenue generations through Airtel live portal for gaming and non-gaming category.
- Continuously analyze, monitor & evaluate market trends & provide notification signals.
- As an alliance manager; working with content partners like jump games, gameloft etc. for content planning and their content promotion on airtel platform.
- Responsible for getting visibility of non-gaming products on Airtel Live portal.

EDUCATIONAL CREDENTIALS

MBA – Telecom & IT, 2009 with 74%, BITM - Pune.

B.E. – Electronics & Communication, 2006 with 66%, MIET - Jammu

Certifications – Digital Marketing by Jio (Oct'18 – Oct'19), Digital Marketing by Google (Dec'19 – No expiry).

Languages – English (full professional proficiency), Hindi (native & bilingual proficiency)